There you go.
（木こノ葉はの里さとの忍）よーし よし
ん？ こんな朝早く どっからだ？
Where'd this one come from
so early in the morning?
Th-This is Takamaru, the fastest
messenger in all the Hidden Sand!
な！ こいつは砂隠れ最速の
タカ丸マルじゃないか
（木ノ葉の里の忍）あ…
Break!
解！
これは…
What's this...?!
It's a level-one emergency message!
第１級の緊急通信文
すぐに暗号班に連絡を
Contact the Cipher Corps
immediately!
It's sure been a long time
since I've been on a mission...
（うずまきナルト）
任務に就くのも久しぶりだな
I'm so excited!
ワクワクするってばよ
Naruto, accept the mission
without complaint,
（春野はるのサクラ）ナルト
どんな任務を言い渡されても
文句を言わずに ちゃんと受けるのよ
no matter what we're ordered to do.
I know!
（ナルト）ああ
分かってるってばよ
I hope so...
（はたけカカシ）だと いいけど
Move it, move it!
（くノ一）どいた どいた！
（ナルト･サクラ）うわあ
What was that?
（サクラ）何？
Watch it, you! Be more careful!
危ねえじゃねえか
気をつけろってばよ
So the Cipher Corps
was summoned, huh...?
（カカシ）暗号班が呼び出されたか
Then what the bird from earlier
brought must've been...
すると さっきの鳥が
運んできたのは…
You said there's
a level-one emergency message?
（くノ一）
第１級の緊急通信文だと？
Are you sure?
間違いないのか
Yes. It's right here...
（木ノ葉の里の忍）はい ここに
（くノ一）砂からか…
It's from the Sand, huh...?
Break!
解！
That message coming here means...
（木ノ葉の里の忍）
そいつが きたってことは
砂に 何かあったに違いない
No doubt something's happened
in the Sand!
Okay!
（くノ一）分かった
すぐに解読する
I'll get right to deciphering it!
♪～
～♪
Team Kakashi, Deployed
（カンクロウ）
烏からすのスピードに
Who'd have thought you could keep up
with Crow's speed...
ついてこられる とはなあ
（サソリ）ハエが
止まりそうだったぜ
It looked like the fly was
about to land, you see.
（カンクロウ）くっ…
I remember now.
（デイダラ）思い出した うん
この人柱力じんちゅうりきには
何人かの兄弟がいたな
This Jinchuriki guy had some siblings.
その中に傀儡くぐつを使うヤツが
いるって聞いた
And I heard that one of them
uses Puppets...
This is probably that guy...
たぶん こいつがそうだな うん
I think his name was Kantaro...
I mean, Kanpachi, or something...?
名前は確か カンタロウ
いや カンパチだったか？
（カンクロウ）カンクロウだ
It's Kankuro!
くっ…
（サソリ）お前の相手は
俺だって言ってるだろうが
I'm telling you I'm  your opponent.
お前も見てねえで
さっさと行け 邪魔だ
And you quit gawking
and get out of here.
You're in the way.
（デイダラ）そうだな
そうさせてもらう うん
You're right... I'll be going, then.
Hey, hold it!
おい 待て！
Don't make me repeat myself...
（サソリ）何度も言わせるな
I'm  your opponent...
お前の相手は俺だ
（カンクロウ）
チッ さっさと こいつを片づけて
追いかけるしかないじゃん
It looks like I'll have to take care
of this guy
and then go after the other one...
You're sure unlucky...
（デイダラ）運がないな
サソリの旦那は恐らく お前にとって
最悪の相手だ うん
My man Sasori just might be
the worst possible opponent for you.
（バキ）まだ トラップが
残っているかもしれん
There might still be
some traps remaining...
（バキ）慎重にな
Be careful...
（砂すなの里さとの忍）追跡部隊
出動準備 完了しました
Preparations for mobilization of
the tracking unit have been completed.
（バキ）よし すぐに
カンクロウを追いかけろ
All right, go after Kankuro immediately.
敵を見つけても
極力 戦闘は避けるんだぞ
Even if you find the enemy,
avoid battle as best you can.
あくまでも目的は
敵のアジトの発見だ
Our only goal is to find
the enemy hideout.
（砂の里の忍たち）はっ
- Yes, sir!
- Yes,sir!
アジトを発見次第
すぐに風影かぜかげ様 奪還チームを出す
We'll send out the Kazekage rescue team
as soon as we find their hideout.
必ず情報を持ち帰ってこい ゆけ！
You'd better come back
with some information!
Get going!
（砂の里の忍たち）はっ
- Yes, sir!
（バキ）カンクロウ…
くれぐれも ムチャはするなよ
Kankuro... Make sure you don't do
anything reckless...
見せてやろうじゃん！
俺の カラクリ演劇を
I'll show you my Puppet Show!
There! There!
ほらほら！
You're pretty good...
However...
やるじゃん けど…
途中から黒蟻くろありが消えたのは
気付かなかっただろ
You didn't notice that
the Black Ant was gone, did you?
いくぜ
Here goes!
からくり演劇
Puppet Show!
黒秘技 危機一髪
Puppet Show
Secret Black Move Iron Maiden!
The show's over.
終劇
（ナルト）はあ？ 金塊輸送の護衛
Whaaat?!
A guard for gold bullion
transport convoy?!
（綱手つなで）ああん！
なんか文句あんのか こら
Huh? You got a problem?!
思いっきりＣランクじゃん
That's totally a C-rank mission!
そんな任務
ノーサンキューだってばよ
I'll just have to say no thanks
to a mission like that...
And here I just told him
not to complain.
（サクラ）文句 言わないって
言ったばかりなのに…
Please don't act so selfish...
（カカシ）あんまりワガママ
言わないでちょうだいよ
怒られんの俺なんだから
I'm the one she's going to get mad at...
（綱手）やっぱり こういう
リアクションか やれやれ
I knew he'd react like this...
Good grief...
Ohh, just as you thought...
（シズネ）アハハハッ
やっぱりですね アハハハッ…
（うみのイルカ）
はあ ナルト お前 精神的には
全然 成長してないのな
Naruto, you haven't matured
mentally at all, have you...?
（綱手）ナルト 一応 お前の
復帰戦ということを考えて
Naruto...
I gave you an easier mission since
this is more or less a comeback for you...
軽めの任務に しておいたんだが
よけいな お世話だってばよ
I didn't ask for this!
I-I'm sorry, Master! I'll give him
a good scolding later...
すいません 師匠
あとで私がよく言っておきますから
（サクラ）
このバカ あんた師匠の恐ろしさを
知らないから そんな口が…
Y-You moron!
You can talk like that
because you don't know
how frightening she can be... Cha!
しゃーんなろー！
The details of the mission
are written here.
（綱手）任務の詳細は
ここに書いてある
Right!
（カカシ）はい
（ナルト）
ったく ３代目のじいちゃんは
もっと物分かりがよかったってばよ
Geez, man...
The old man Third Hokage
was much more understanding ...
ああん なんか言ったか！
Huh? Did you say something?!
（サクラ）
だから いいかげんにしろ！
Hey! Knock it off!
大変です ５代目！
Th-There's trouble...Fifth Hokage!
（綱手）なんだ 騒々しい
What's all the commotion...?
（くノ一）
先ほど砂から緊急通信が…
We just received an emergency message
from the Sand...
（ナルト）あ… 砂？
The Sand...?!
（綱手）緊急通信だと？
Did you say an emergency message?!
（くノ一）解読したものです
This is what we have deciphered...
何！
What?!
砂！
Sand?!
砂分身だと
A sand clone...?
（イルカ）こ… これは！
Oh...my god...
（シズネ）そんな！
It can't be...
（ナルト）なあ 何が
あったんだってばよ？
Hey... What happened...?
砂隠れの風影が 暁あかつきという
組織の者に連れ去られた
The Kazekage of the Hidden Sand
has been taken
by members of the organization
called the Akatsuki.
（カカシ）ああ
（サクラ）あっ
あ… 我愛羅があらが
Gaara...
また あいつらか
Those guys again, huh...?
（綱手）
暁に関しては我々のほうが
多くの情報を持っている
We have more information
concerning the Akatsuki.
And so the Hidden Sand has
officially requested our help...
そこで砂隠れから
正式に応援を要請してきた
（シズネ）ああ！ 綱手様
まさか カカシ班を…
Lady Tsunade, don't tell me
you're going to have Team Kakashi...?!
緊急時だ のんびり
人選している暇はない
This is a time of emergency.
I can't be wasting time
on personnel selection.
それに 実際に暁と戦った者もいる
And besides, we've got someone here
who's actually fought against
the Akatsuki...
（シズネ）それは そうですが…
I understand that, but...
（綱手）これよりカカシ班に
改めて任務を言い渡す
I will now issue Team Kakashi
a new mission.
直ちに砂隠れの里へ行き
状況を把握し木ノ葉へ伝達
Go to the Village Hidden
in the Sand immediately,
find out what's going on and
report back to the Leaf...
その後 砂隠れの命に従い
彼らをバックアップしろ
After that, you will follow the orders
of the Hidden Sand
and provide them with back-up!
（カンクロウ）うう… なぜだ？
How...?
How...?!
なぜなんだ？
How can he read
my movements like this...?
なぜ こうまで こちらの
動きが読まれるんだ
しかも ヤツは さっきから
ほとんど動いてねえ
And on top of that,
he's hardly moved at all the whole time...
What's the matter?
Are you already finished...?
（サソリ）
どうした もう終わりか？
（カンクロウ）くっ…
Like hell I am!
んなわけねえじゃん！
Poisoned Mist Inferno...
毒霧地獄 バリバリ100連発！
Consecutive Needle Combo!
（カンクロウ）ウッ…
（サソリ）終わりか？
Are you finished?
No way... How is he not affected by
being in the Poisoned Mist?!
（カンクロウ）
バカな！ 毒霧の中に
いたってのに平気なのかよ
Making people wait any longer than this
goes against my policy...
（サソリ）
これ以上 人を待たせるのは
俺のポリシーに反するんでな
そろそろ こちらから
いかせてもらうぜ
I think it's just about my turn now!
山椒魚さんしょううおは鉄壁の防御
Salamander has an iron wall defense...
数万トンの岩の直撃にも
耐えることができる
It can withstand a direct hit from
a few thousand tons of rocks...
フフフッ
You won't be able to inflict even
a scratch on me.
お前は俺に 傷１つ
つけることもできねえ
It's safe to say the defensive strength
of that puppet
（サソリ）
確かに その傀儡くぐつの防御能力は
最高レベルと言っていいだろう
is indeed of the highest level.
However...
だが 弱点が ないわけじゃない
There's always a weakness.
（カンクロウ）ムダだ！
It's futile!
あ！
N-No way...
バ… バカな
山椒魚さんしょううおの弱点を
ひと目で見破っただと？
He figured out Salamander's weakness
in one glance...?
う… うわ！
うう…
No matter how strong the puppet may be,
（サソリ）例え
どんな頑丈な傀儡くぐつでも
the movable parts of the joints
are weaker than the other parts.
稼働部分である関節は
ほかより強度が劣るものだ
Now then, shall we go for the finale?
さて フィナーレといくか
（湯飲みにヒビが入った音）
（テマリ）ん…
（テマリ）こういうのは
あまり信じないんだが
I usually don't believe
in stuff like this, but...
なんだか胸騒ぎがする
I've kind of got
a bad feeling about this...
（カンクロウ）てやあ！
How...?
（カンクロウ）
なぜだ？ なぜ こうまで
仕込みの手順を読まれるんだ
How can he read
my hidden weapon attack schemes...?
（サソリ）筋はいい
だが 相手が悪かったな
You've got solid talent...
However, you picked
the wrong opponent.
お前の傀儡くぐつ
毒仕込みのカラクリは
Your puppets
with the hidden poison weapons...
全て お見通しだ
I can see through them all...
（カンクロウ）
ああ 烏からす 黒蟻くろあり 山椒魚さんしょううお！
Crow! Black Ant! Salamander!
This is the first time
（カンクロウ）ここまで仕込みを
読まれたのは初めてだ
my hidden weapon attacks
have been read like this...
（サソリ）フフッ
不思議そうな顔してる
You look puzzled...
You're wondering how
I figured out your attacks, huh?
なぜ仕込みがバレた？
そりゃあ そうだ
Of course I did.
Crow...
烏からす 黒蟻くろあり 山椒魚さんしょううお
Black Ant...
Salamander...
この３体の傀儡くぐつ人形を
作ったのは ほかでもない
The one who created these
three puppets is none other...than me!
この俺だ！
（カンクロウ）な！
（カエル）ゲロゲロ ゲロゲロ
（カエル）ゲーロゲロ ゲーロゲロ
（カエル）ゲロゲロ
（自来也じらいや）うわ！
（自来也）ええ… ろ…？
（カエル）ゲコ
その巻物は…
That scroll...?!
バカもん！ 早く見せろ
You idiot! Hurry up and show it to me!
（カエル）ゲコ
（自来也）ん～ 何々？
砂隠れの里の風影が…
What...?
The Kazekage of the Hidden Sand
has been...
こりゃ のんびり寝ている
場合じゃないのう
Looks like this isn't the time
to be sleeping like this!
（サソリ）少々 人を待たせる
ことになってしまったが
I ended up making
someone wait a bit...
But I never thought my opponent
would be
お下がりを持っている
カワイイ後輩が相手とは
one of my adorable juniors
using hand-me-downs.
久々に楽しい戦いだったぞ
I haven't had such a fun fight
in quite some time.
Then, you're...the celebrated master
craftsman of the puppet unit,
じゃあ てめえが傀儡くぐつ部隊の
天才造形師とうたわれた
Sasori of the Red Sand?!
赤砂のサソリだってのか？
I'm honored that a kid like you
knows my name.
（サソリ）お前のようなガキにまで
名を知られているとは 光栄だな
You left the Sand over twenty years ago.
20年以上も前に
砂を抜けたお前が なぜ…
What're you doing here?!
（サソリ）死ぬ前に
そんなに聞いてどうする？
What's the point of asking such
a thing before you die?
あ… うあ
くっ… あ…
体が しびれてきやがった
My body's getting numb...
Don't tell me he also uses poison...
まさか こいつも毒を…
But when?
だが いつ？
そうか あのとき！
I know! At that moment!
The poison's circulating, huh...?
You're finished!
（サソリ）
毒が回ってきたな とどめだ
ん？
ふん
苦しむだけだというのに
そうまでして生きていたいなら
You're just going to suffer.
But if you want to live that badly...
I won't finish you off!
とどめは やめだ
ただ その毒だ
３日ともたずに お前は死ぬ
However, that poison will kill you
in less than three days.
Gaara...
（カンクロウ）我愛羅…
ちっきしょう
Damn it...!
There he is! He's over there!
（砂の里の忍）いたぞ あそこだ
倒れてる
He's collapsed!
And his puppets are smashed...
（砂の里の忍）傀儡くぐつもバラバラだぞ
Okay, we're off now!
（ナルト）んじゃ
行ってくるってばよ
では綱手師匠 行って参ります
We'll be back, Master.
Right...
（綱手）ああ
（イルカ）ん…
Naruto, good luck!
ナルト 頑張れよ
Thanks.
おう
おお これから任務か ナルト？
Hey!
Are you off on a mission now, Naruto?
That's right!
（ナルト）押忍
Oh, more importantly.
（自来也）おっと それより
綱手 情報だ
Tsunade, I've got some information
for you.
砂隠れの風影が…
- The Kazekage of the Hidden Sand...
- I know.
（綱手）知ってる 今から
こいつらを砂に送るところだ
I'm just about to send them off
to the Sand now.
Right, right.
うん うん
（自来也）暁とナルトのことは
お前も知っとるだろうのォ
You know about the Akatsuki
and Naruto, don't you...?
緊急事態だからな
最善の選択をしたまでだ
It's an emergency situation you see...
I just made the best choice I could.
まったく お前は…
Oh, come on...
Naruto, come here for a second.
ナルト ちょっと こっちこい
（ナルト）ん？
Hm?
いいか ナルト
暁 相手に決して無理はするな
Listen up, Naruto.
Don't get reckless against the Akatsuki.
あいつら俺に用があるんだから
They've got business with me.
今度こそ こっちから
出向いてやらあ
So this time I'll go to them!
You have indeed gotten stronger...
確かにお前は強くなったがのォ
冷静を欠けば 必ず
墓穴を掘ることになるぞ
But if you don't keep cool,
you'll just be asking for trouble.
すぐに熱くなるのは
お前の悪い癖だのォ
Losing your cool right away
is a bad habit of yours.
ナルト 分かってるとは思うが
あの力は使うなよ
Naruto... I think you know...
But don't use that power.
（ナルト）分かってるってばよ
I know...
Kakashi...
カカシ ナルトがあまり
ムチャしないよう見張ってくれ
Keep an eye on Naruto and make sure
he doesn't do anything too reckless.
I'm counting on you. Okay?
頼んだぞ のォ
Okay.
（カカシ）はい
Kakashi Sensei, Sakura,
let's get a move on!
（ナルト）カカシ先生
サクラちゃん
さっさと行くってばよ
H-Hey, wait up!
（サクラ）
ああ… ちょっと待ってよ
We're off.
（カカシ）では
Oh boy...
ったく のォ
Are you worried?
心配か？
No, I'm not...
いえ あいつは もう
私の心配するような
He's no longer a weak Shinobi
I need to worry about...
弱い忍びでは ありませんから
それにサクラも…
And the same goes for Sakura.
（綱手）成長とは
不思議なもんだなあ
Growth is sure a mysterious thing.
Hang on, Gaara!
（ナルト）待ってろよ 我愛羅
♪～
～♪
What's the matter, Kankuro?
ん どうしたカンクロウ？
Actually, my makeup remover
doesn't really agree with my skin.
実はメイク落としが合わなくてよ
At a time like that, you need
this makeup remover gauze.
そんなときは
このメイク拭き取りガーゼ
It's gentle on the skin as
the
ミクロの繊維が毛穴の奥の
汚れまで かき出すから
肌に優しくメイクオフだ
おお 隈取くまどり 落ちる落ちる
おまけに今 購入すると
同じ物がもう１つに
持ち運び便利な
専用収納ケースまで付いてくるんだ
そりゃ大変だ
すぐ 砂の売店まで
急ぐっきゃねえじゃん
次回「人柱力じんちゅうりきの涙」
（綱手）中忍(ちゅうにん)試験のさなか
始まった木ノ葉崩し
木ノ葉を裏切り
大蛇丸おろちまるに加担した砂の襲撃を受け
３代目 火影ほかげが絶命
木ノ葉の受けた被害は甚大であった
後に風影は大蛇丸に
暗殺されていたことが判明
砂隠れの里は 事件の発端が
大蛇丸によるものと公表し
全面的な降伏を宣言
国力の復旧を急務としていた
木ノ葉は砂との同名を締結した
現在では新人育成に
木ノ葉の演習プログラムを
取り入れるなど 交流も深い
ちなみに シカマルと
テマリの交際疑惑だが
シカマル当人が中忍ちゅうにん試験の
打ち合わせとコメント
ナルトの早とちりだった模様
以上 今後も木ノ葉と砂は
良好な同盟関係を
築いていくと思われる